実に　いい。
How wonderful...
いい顔だぁ！
I really do love that look.
でも俺　あの時　ワクワクしたんだ。
But I was pretty excited, as well.
え？ 怖くて　逃げ出したいって 思ったけど　それもできなくて…。
I was so scared, I wanted to run away. But I couldn't.
でも　ワクワクしたんだ　変だよね。
And at the same time, I was excited. Isn't that strange?
どうやら　間に合ったようだ。
Looks like we made it in time.
レオリオ…。
Leorio...
レオリオ！
Leorio!
あぁ　痛って！ 何で俺　こんなケガしてんだ？
Man, that stings... Why am I all beat up?
え？
Huh?
どうも　記憶が ハッキリしなくってよ。
My memory is kinda hazy.
このまま　いわないほうが よさそうだな。
We probably shouldn't tell
him what happened.
うん。
Yeah...
ゴン！ キルア！
Gon. Killua!
お前　よく ここまで　たどり着いたな。
I can't believe you actually got here...
もう　無理だと思ってたぜ。
I thought you were done for.
レオリオの香水のにおいを たどったんだ。
I just tracked Leorio's cologne.
におい!?　それだけ？
Cologne? That was how?
お前　やっぱ　相当変わってんな。
You definitely are weird.
皆さん　お疲れさまでした！
Excellent work, everyone.
ここ　ビスカ森林公園が ２次試験会場となります。
Phase Two of the exam will occur here,
in the Biska Forest Park.
では　私は　これで 皆さんの健闘をお祈りします。
So, I shall take my leave. Best of luck to all of you.
１次試験を通過した 受験者の諸君　中へ！
Will all applicants who passed
the First Phase please enter?
ようこそ！ 私が２次試験試験官の　メンチよ。
Welcome. I'm Menchi, the Second Phase examiner.
同じく　ブハラ。
And I'm Buhara, the other examiner.
何だ？　この音は
Wh-What was that sound?
どうやら腹ペコのようね。 もう　ペコペコだよ。
You must be hungry. I'm starving...
そんなわけで　２次試験は…。
There you have it.
Phase Two will involve...
料理よ！
...cooking!
りょ…　料理？ ちょっと待て　料理だと!?
C-Cooking? Wait! Cooking?
俺達は　ハンター試験を 受けに来てんだぜ？
We're here to take the Hunter Exam!
そうよ 私達を満足させる料理を作る これが２次試験の課題よ。
That's quite right. Your challenge for the Second Phase is to produce
a dish that will satisfy our palate.
何で料理なんだよ！
Why do we have to cook?!
なぜなら　私達は 美食ハンターだから。
That's because we are Gourmet Hunters.
あ？　プッ　ハハハ…！
Huh?
ったく　拍子抜けだぜ！
Man, what a letdown.
美食ハンターだとよ。
They're Gourmet Hunters...
厄介な２人が 試験官に選ばれたものです
Their selection as examiners
could prove problematic.
この２次試験で５０人　いや
Only fifty applicants...
課題次第では１０人以下に なってしまうかもしれません
No, depending on the task, it's possible that fewer than ten
applicants will pass Phase Two.
で　美食ハンターさん 一体　どんな料理を 作りゃあいいんだい？
So, Gourmet Hunters,
what are we supposed to make?
ブハラ！
Buhara.
指定する食材は　ブタだよ。
The required ingredient is pork.
ブタ？　ブタって あのブタか？
Pork? As in pig meat?
この　ビスカの森にいるブタなら 種類は自由！
You're free to use meat from any
species of Biska Forest pigs.
そのブタを　ここにある 調理器具を使って　作った料理で
You must use the cooking facilities here
to prepare the pork.
俺達２人が揃って 「おいしい」といえば　合格だよ。
And you only pass if we both
find it delicious.
おいしいといっても 味だけじゃ　ダメ。
And we will evaluate more
than just the taste.
料理をナメないでね　分かった？
Don't underestimate the
intricacies of cooking. Got it?
私達２人が満腹になった時点で 試験は終了だからね。
When we've both eaten our fill, the exam will end.
分かった　分かった とっとと始めようぜ！
We get it. We get it. Let's just start.
それじゃあ　２次試験
Then, the exam's Second Phase
スタート！
begins now!
あんたも性格悪いわね。
You have a real nasty streak.
食材選びは　俺の担当だろ？
Choosing the ingredients was my job.
ビスカの森に生息するブタ っていったら １種類だけでしょ？
Only one species of pig lives in
the Biska Forest, correct?
フッ　死ななきゃいいけど。
I hope they don't get themselves killed.
おい　ブタちゃん。
Hey, little piggy?
ブタを捕まえて料理！ １次試験より　ずっと楽だな。
Catch a pig and cook it. This is way easier than the First Phase.
だといいんだがな。 お？
I hope it will be that simple...
おい！　何なんだよ　ゴン！
What was that about, Gon?!
いたよ。 あ？
Found them. Huh?
ブタだ！
Pigs!
おい　骨　食ってんぞ。
Uh... They're chewing on bones.
まさか…
Don't tell me...
肉食!?
They're carnivores?
ん？ 何だ？
Huh? What's that?
何てブタだ！
These pigs are crazy!
グレイト・スタンプ 世界で最も凶暴なブタだ。
The Great Stamp, the world's most ferocious pig.
大きくて頑丈な鼻で 敵をはじき飛ばす。
They use their large, stout noses
to send their enemies flying.
逃げ遅れれば　自分が ブタの食材になっちまうぜ。
If you're too slow, you'll end up
as their dinner.
おりゃ！
Take that!
何!?
What?
ありゃ？
Huh?
ひょっとして…。
Just maybe...
へぇ　あいつら 額が弱点だったのか。
Could their foreheads be
their weak points?
巨大で硬い鼻は もろい額をガードするための 進化というわけだ。
So, the pigs evolved large, strong noses in order to protect
their soft foreheads.
ウッヒャハハ！ あらま　大漁だこと。
Oh, my. They caught a lot.
うむ　今年の受験生は 優秀ですな
This year's applicants are very talented.
しかし　問題は　ここから
However, the difficult part is yet to come.
さぁ！　とっとと食って 合格にしろ！
Now eat the pig and send me
to the next phase.
では　ジャッジタイム。
Okay, it's evaluation time.
実食。
Taste testing.
ウッフフフ！　うんまい！
Tastes good!
焼き過ぎね！　硬くなって 肉　本来のうま味が台無しよ！
It's overcooked. The tough texture ruins the
flavor of the meat.
何　食いもしねえで！
What? You haven't even tried it!
一目瞭然でしょ！ クソっ。
It's plain as day. Damn it...
さぁ　食ってくれ！
Okay... Dive in!
えぇ！　何で!?
Huh? Why?
表面パサパサ　中は生！ 火が強過ぎるのよ！
Charred on the outside,
uncooked inside. Your fire was too strong.
まったく　どいつも　こいつも
Honestly...
バカの一つ覚えみたいに 丸焼きばっかり！
All they're doing is roasting the whole pig,
like it's all they know how to do...
工夫ってもんが 全くないじゃない
None of them has made any effort!
いまだに １人も合格してねえな。
No one's passed yet...
しかも　メンチは まだ　ひと口も食べていない。
And Menchi hasn't even taken a bite...
ちょっと！　誰か１人くらい 私を満足させる奴は　いないの!?
Hey! Can't anyone out there satisfy me?
そうか！　この試験課題は 料理だが 審査の対象は 独創性と観察力とみた！
That's it! This phase of the exam is a cooking test, but they're judging us on originality
and powers of observation.
ふふん。 なるほど。
I see...
どうだい！　俺様の料理。
How do you like my cooking?
お子様ランチかぁ！
Is this supposed to be a kiddy meal?!
次は　俺のだ！
I'm next!
大して変わらんわ！
It's basically the same thing!
次は私だ！
I am next!
ジャッジをお願いする。
Please judge my creation.
ふん　やっと料理っぽいものが 出て来たわね。
Finally, something that
resembles an actual dish...
与えられた器具や 食材を駆使し
The point is to use the provided
facilities and ingredients
いかに　メーンのブタを 引き立てるかがポイント
to highlight the main feature, the pork.
つまり　味は二の次！
In other words, the taste is insignificant!
まずいわ！
Yuck!
えっ。
Huh?
見た目も重要だけど 味が伴ってこそよ！
Appearance is important, but only if it also tastes good.
あんたも４０３番と同レベルね！ ハッ…。
You're no better than #403!
ハッハ　残念だったな！
Too bad!
４０３番と同じレベルか…。
No better than #403...
ヘッヘッヘ！　食った食った もう　お腹いっぱい！
That was so much food, I'm stuffed!
はい　私も　お腹いっぱい！
Yeah, I'm stuffed, too.
てなわけで合格者なし！
Therefore, no one passes.
終了！
We're finished here!
え？　終わり？
It's over? What the hell?
やはり 彼女の悪い癖が出ましたか
As I expected, she's lapsed back
into her old bad habits.
どうします？　会長。
What should we do, Chairman?
仕方あるまい。
I suppose I have no choice.
よし！　出掛けるぞい！
Fine, I'll have to go in person.
合格者ゼロ？ マジかよ！
Zero people passed? Are you serious?
本気でいってんのか？ まさか…　これで終わり？
Does she really mean it? The exam is over?
冗談じゃねえぜ！
This isn't funny!
納得　行かねえな！ こんなの　俺は絶対に認めねえ！
I won't accept it... I absolutely refuse to accept this!
ふざけんな！
In the end, you've still failed. Stop screwing around!
お前らが　ブタを食わせろ というから　こっちは命懸けで…。
You asked for pork, so we risked our lives to—
私は　ブタを使った料理で
I said to prepare the pork in a manner
「おいしいと　いわせろ」と いったのよ！
we both found delicious...
ひとっつも　おいしいと思った 料理なんて　なかったわ。
None of you made anything
remotely delicious.
どいつも　こいつも 似たような料理ばかり。
You all did almost the same thing.
工夫が　なさ過ぎるのよ！
There was no effort made...
ちょっと工夫したと思えば 見た目だけ
Just when I thought someone actually tried,
they only changed the appearance.
味へのこだわりがないし
No one attempted to emphasize the flavor.
料理をナメてるとしか 思えないわ！
I'm positive that none of you
took cooking seriously!
ブタの料理なんて　誰が どう作ったって　大差ねえだろ。
Pork dishes are all the same...
もう一度いってみろ　こら！ 今度　生意気な口たたいたら
Just say that once more.
ケツから　手　突っ込んで 奥歯　ガタガタいわせてやんぞ！
Any more crap from you, and I'll shove my arm up your ass
and knock your teeth out!
ああ メンチの悪い癖が出た
Don't you mess with me! There's Menchi's bad habit again...
そもそも　メンチを満足させられる 料理人なんて
I don't want any lip from a bunch of After all, only a handful of chefs amateurs who can't even roast a pig!
世界中に数えるほどしか いないのに
in the entire world can satisfy Menchi. Hey! What did you just say?
もう一回　いってみろ　こら！
Why don't you repeat it to my face?!
要するに　あんたらは
In other words, you people
自ら工夫して未知なるものに 挑戦する気概がないのよ。
don't have the guts to try anything new.
黙れ！　俺が目指してるのは コックでもグルメでもねえ。
Shut up! I'm not trying to become
a cook or a gourmet...
ハンターだ！ そうだ　そうだ！
I want to be a Hunter! Yeah! Yeah!
俺は　賞金首ハンターを 目指してんだ！
My goal is to become a Black List Hunter.
美食ハンターごときに 合否を決められたくねえな！
I refuse to let a mere Gourmet Hunter
decide my fate!
美食ハンターごときが試験官で 残念だったわね。
Too bad you got stuck with a mere Gourmet Hunter as an examiner...
また来年　頑張れば？
Better luck next year?
この　ふざけんじゃ　ねえ!!
Why, you... Don't mock me!
だってさぁ　俺が手出さなきゃ メンチ　あいつをやってたろ？
Buhara, don't interfere. Well... If I hadn't intervened,
you'd have killed him, right?
フン　まぁね。
Probably.
いっとくけどね
Let me clarify this...
私らも　食材　探して　猛獣の巣に 入ることだって　珍しくないのよ。
We frequently venture into the dens of ferocious beasts,
searching for ingredients.
武芸なんて　ハンターやってりゃ 嫌でも身につくのよ。
Every Hunter knows some form
of martial art.
注意力も　未知のものに挑戦する 気概もない。
You lack focus and the willingness
to experiment.
それだけで 十分　ハンターの資格なしよ！
That alone disqualifies you
from becoming Hunters!
それにしても 合格者ゼロは ちと　厳し過ぎやせんか？
That said, it would be excessive to fail
every single applicant.
あれは… ハンター協会のマーク！
That's the symbol of the
Hunters Association!
審査委員会か？
Is it someone from the
Selection Committee?
な…　何者だ？　あの　じいさん
Wh-Who's that geezer?
審査委員会の会長であり ハンター試験の最高責任者
The Chairman of the
Selection Committee. He's in charge of the Hunter Exam...
ネテロ会長よ。
Chairman Netero.
まっ　責任者といっても しょせん裏方。
Well, I work behind the scenes.
こんなトラブルが起きた時の 処理係みたいなもんじゃ。
I only take action when there's
an issue, like now.
で　メンチ君。 はい。
So, Menchi-kun... Yes, sir.
君は　未知のものに挑戦する 気概を問うた結果
You failed all of the applicants because
全員　その態度に問題あり
you disapproved of their reluctance
不合格と思ったわけかね？
to try new things?
いえ　受験者に美食ハンターを 軽んじる発言をされ
No, sir... I lost my cool when one
of the candidates
つい　カッとなり…
insulted Gourmet Hunters.
必要以上に　審査が 厳しくなってしまいました。
And I made the exam harder
than necessary.
つまり　自分でも審査不十分だと 分かっとるわけだな？
In other words, you're aware that
this exam was unacceptable.
はい　料理のこととなると われを忘れるんです。
Yes, sir. When cooking is involved,
I lose control.
試験官　失格ですね。
I'm unqualified to be an examiner.
私は試験官を降りますので 試験のやり直しをお願いします！
I will resign as examiner, so please redo the Second Phase!
ふむ　しかし　急に別の試験官を 用意するのも面倒じゃ。
But it would be difficult to find another examiner on such short notice.
申し訳ありません。
I apologize...
よし！　では　こうしよう。
Very well. How about this?
試験官は続けてもらう ただし　新しい試験には
I'd like you to continue serving
as an examiner. But you must also participate
君にも実演という形で 参加してもらう
in the new test you propose.
…というのは　いかがかな？
Is that acceptable?
そのほうが受験者も 納得　行きやすいじゃろう。
I'm certain that will help the applicants to accept the results.
そうですね それじゃあ　新しい課題は
That's true... Then the new challenge will be
ゆで卵ってことで！
boiled eggs!
ゆで卵？
Boiled eggs?
会長　私達を飛行船で
Chairman, can you take us
to Mt. Split-in-Half
マフタツ山まで 運んでいただけませんか？
in your airship?
マフタツ山か　なるほどの… いいとも！
Mt. Split-in-Half? I see what you're doing. Certainly, I can.
さぁ　みんな 崖下をのぞいてみて！
Now, everyone... Look down there.
何だ　あれは…
Wh-What is that?
クモワシの巣よ。 あんなとこに巣を作るんだ。
A Spider Eagle's web. They build webs down there?
巣の下のほうを　よく見て！
Look below the web.
あれは…。 あれが　クモワシの卵。
Those are... Those are Spider Eagle eggs.
クモワシは 天敵から卵を守るため 深い谷間に巣を作り 卵を産むのじゃ。
Spider Eagles build their webs in deep ravines, to protect their eggs from predators.
それ故　世界で最も入手困難な 食材の１つでの
This makes their eggs one of the most difficult
ingredients to obtain.
別名　「幻の卵」と呼ばれておる。
The eggs are also known as dream eggs.
ちょ…　ちょっと待て　まさか？
W-Wait a minute... You don't mean we...
その　まさかよ。 えぇ!?
I sure do. What?
ハァ…。 たとえ　卵を取れたとしても どうやって上がって来る気だ？
Even if she can grab some eggs, how will she climb back up?
単なる自殺行為じゃねえか！
Is she trying to kill herself?
いや　違う。 え？
No, she's not. Huh?
わぁ！ おもしれぇ！
That looks fun...
この谷底から吹き上がる 上昇気流は
This ravine has updrafts
卵から　かえったヒナが 巣へと飛び上がれるように なっておるのじゃ！
that help the hatched chicks
fly up to the web.
はい　これで　ゆで卵を作るのよ！
There. Now I just need to boil the egg.
じょ…　冗談だろ。
Y-You must be joking.
こんなもん　まともな神経で 飛び降りられるわけがねえや。
No reasonable person would
jump down there...
こういうの待ってたんだ！ えぇ!? あっ。
I've been waiting for this!
よし！　俺も！
Okay! Count me in!
待って！ 最後まで説明を聞いて！
Wait! I haven't finished explaining everything!
ヘヘっ　お先に！
Catch you later.
俺達も行くか！ 今　飛んじゃ　ダメだ。
Let's go! Not yet.
どうして？ 風だよ。
Why not? There's no wind.
風は常に吹いているわけじゃ ないからな。
There isn't always an updraft.
その風は　いつ吹くんだよ！ 待って。
When's the next one? Wait.
うわっ　何だ!?
What?
この人数の重みで 糸が耐えられないんだ！
The web won't hold us all!
ゴン　まだ？
Gon, not yet?
クソ！　風なんて待ってられるか！
Damn, I can't wait for an updraft!
切れるぜ！
It's gonna snap!
今だ！
Now!
ホッホッホ…。 残りは？
And the rest of you?
ギブアップみたいね。 やめるのも　勇気じゃて。
I guess you quit. It takes courage to concede, too.
こりゃ　うめぇ！　市販の卵とは 比べもんにならねえ！
This is damned good. Much better than the eggs
you buy in a store...
まさに　幻の卵だ！
I can see why they're
called dream eggs.
ねぇ　トードーさん。 あ？
Hey, Todo-san.
よかったら食べてみない？
Would you like a bite?
ハッ　うめぇ！
It's delicious...
おいしいものを 発見した時の喜び
Now you've experienced the joy
of discovering
少しは味わってくれたかしら？
how good something can taste.
こちとら これに命懸けてんのよね！
We're risking our lives for that joy.
はぁ…　今年は完敗だ。
I was completely outclassed this year.
また来年　出直して来ます！
I'll be back next year!
賞金首ハンターだろうと 美食ハンターだろうと ハンターを名乗るには 大きな覚悟が必要だと 思い知らされた受験者達
The applicants have learned that, whether you're a Black List Hunter
or a Gourmet Hunter, calling yourself a Hunter requires an
enormous amount of determination.
残りは　４２名
Only 42 applicants remain.